Guide to the Vassar College Archives Files, circa 1855-1969 (bulk 1860-1914)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Archives Files
circa 1855-1969
1860-1914
Vassar College
13.6 cubic feet (15 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
An artificial collection of materials documenting the history of Vassar College, collected by various departments of the Library over several decades. Materials include letters, photographs, programs, college circulars and other publications, building specifications, contracts, bills and receipts, inventories, accounts, committee minutes, architectural and landscape drawings, reports, and club constitutions and records.
Scope and Content Note
An artificial collection of materials documenting the history of Vassar College, collected by various departments of the Library from multiple sources over several decades. Materials include photographs, letters, programs, college circulars and other publications, building specifications, contracts, bills and receipts, inventories, accounts, committee minutes, architectural and landscape drawings, reports, and club constitutions and records. Specific items include letters on the structure of college education for women, admission requirements, and references for some of Vassar's first students, 1860-1865; letters and applications of professors and staff, 1860-1864; correspondence on the role of alumnae at Vassar, 1884-1915; college journal containing entries on events, meetings, speakers, domestic concerns, and social life, 1870-1871; notebooks of directives from the President's Office to faculty and students, 1869-1883; correspondence of Adelaide Underhill and President MacCracken about the Library, 1915-1924; reports and correspondence relating to the Maids' Clubhouse, 1914; minutes, reports, memoranda, and correspondence of college trustees, 1861-1936; original manuscript and typescript reports by the college president, 1866-1918; correspondence, sketches, estimates, and bills relating to construction of the first college facilities; and manuscript and typescript reports from College departments, the comptroller, the Lady Principal, the Library, and the Physician, 1866-1869.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Henry Noble MacCracken Papers
Subject Headings
Names:
Caldwell, Samuel L. (Samuel Lunt), 1820-1889; Jewett, Milo P.; MacCracken, H. N. (Henry Noble), 1880-1970; Raymond, John H. (John Howard), 1814-1878; Renwick, James, 1818-1895; Taylor, James Monroe, 1848-1916; Underhill, Adelaide, 1860-1936
Organizations:
Vassar College--Admission; Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; Vassar College--Buildings; Vassar College--Employees; Vassar College--Faculty; Vassar College--History; Vassar College--Presidents; Vassar College--Students; Vassar College. Board of Trustees; Vassar College. Comptroller; Vassar College. Lady Principal; Vassar College. Library
Subjects:
Landscape architecture--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women--Education; Women--Societies and clubs; Women college students--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
Document Types:
Account books; Administrative records; Architectural drawings; Correspondence; Financial records; Minutes (administrative records); Photographs; Reports
VCL Categories:
Vassar College Administrative Offices and Functions; Vassar College Presidents
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, May 2007. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, June 2024.
Acquisition Information
An artificial collection, collected by various departments of the Library from multiple sources over several decades.
Folder List
- Admissions — Requirements for admission, letters of acceptance, letters of reference, 1860-1865 (Box 1, Folder 1.1)
- Admissions — Requirements for admission, exam cards, 1866-1888 (Box 1, Folder 1.2)
- Admissions — Admission of Packer Institute Students, letters from Packer President Truman J. Backus, report of LeRoy Cooley on visit to Packer, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 1.3)
- Advertising — (includes undated clippings), 1865, 1881, 1884, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.4)
- Advertising — Broadsheet, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.5)
- Alumnae Association of Vassar College — SEE ALSO: Associate Alumnae
- Alumnae Association of Vassar College — AAVC Reports, Letters to Alumnae, 1871-1894, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.6)
- Alumnae Association of Vassar College — Academic Council of Alumnae Correspondence between members of council and President Taylor, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 1.7)
- Alumnae Association of Vassar College — Circular Letter to Trustees Concerning the State of the College, 1884; [2 Copies of letter, ITS, IMS] (Box 1, Folder 1.8)
- Alumnae Association of Vassar College — Papers Concerning Alumnae Representation, petitions to Board of Trustees, corr., outline of a plan for Alumnae Representation, 1887-1888, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.9)
- Alumnae Association of Vassar College — Alumnae Monthly Correspondence between Elsie Hill and President Taylor re: Vassar Alumnae Monthly, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1.10)
- Alumnae Association of Vassar College — Alumnae Trustees plan for nomination of alumnae trustees, 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.11)
- Alumnae Association of Vassar College — Letter to Mary C. Raymond from her sister, reporting on activities of the VC Alumnae Association and a visit to Vassar College, [1885?] (Box 15, Folder 9.1)
- Ancient Languages — Applications for Chairman and Professorships, 1862-1865 (Box 1, Folder 1.12)
- Modern Languages — Applications for Chairman and Professorships A-J, 1863-1865 (Box 1, Folder 1.13)
- Modern Languages — Applications for Chairman and Professorships K, 1863-1865 (Box 1, Folder 1.14)
- Modern Languages — Applications for Chairman and Professorships L, 1864-1865 (Box 1, Folder 1.15)
- Modern Languages — Applications for Chairman and Professorships M-Z, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 1.16)
- Ancient and Modern Languages Department — Reports, 1865-1869 (Box 1, Folder 1.17)
- Ancient and Modern Languages Department — Reports, 1869-1872 (Box 1, Folder 1.18)
- Ancient and Modern Languages Department — Reports, 1872-1880 (Box 1, Folder 1.19)
- Ancient and Modern Languages Department — Reports, 1881-1889 (Box 1, Folder 1.20)
- Anderson, Martin Brewer (VC Trustee, President of U. of Rochester) — Letters to Matthew Vassar, Cyrus Swan, John H. Raymond, and Samuel Caldwell, 1860-1880 (Box 1, Folder 1.21)
- Applications — Applications for positions of bookkeeper, Engineering/ Machinist, Assistant Housekeeper, Mechanic, Nurse, Steam Operator, 1863-1865 (Box 1, Folder 1.22)
- Applications — Applications for position of Matron, 1862-1865 (Box 1, Folder 1.23)
- Art Department — Reports, 1885-1891 (Box 1, Folder 1.24)
- Art Department — Reports, 1891-1898 (Box 1, Folder 1.25)
- Art Department — Reports, 1900-1905, 1911-1913 (Box 1, Folder 1.26)
- Art Gallery — Correspondence re: purchases for Gallery, 1873-1875, 1893, 1895, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 1.27)
- Art Gallery — Correspondence re: Ehrich gift, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1.28)
- Art Gallery — Inventory of Art Collection, by Henry Van Ingen, Professor of Art, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 1.29)
- Art Gallery — Report of the [Trustees] Committee, 1864, 1877-1878 (Box 1, Folder 1.30)
- Art Gallery — Rules of the Art Gallery by Board of Trustees, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 1.31)
- Associate Alumnae — Correspondence re: Barrows Resolution, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1.32)
- Associate Alumnae — Correspondence, 1911-1920, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.33)
- Associate Alumnae — Meeting, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 1.34)
- Astronomy Department — Application (Abbe) for Professor of Astronomy, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 1.35)
- Astronomy Department — Reports, 1865-1872 (Box 1, Folder 1.36)
- Astronomy Department — Reports, 1872-1878 (Box 1, Folder 1.37)
- Astronomy Department — Reports, 1878-1881, 1882-1888 (Box 1, Folder 1.38)
- Astronomy Department — Reports, 1888-1892, 1893-1897 (Box 1, Folder 1.39)
- Astronomy Department — Reports, 1897-1903 (Box 1, Folder 1.40)
- Astronomy Department — Reports, 1903-1910 (Box 1, Folder 1.41)
- Astronomy Department — Reports, 1910-1914, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.42)
- Athletic Association — re: new tennis courts, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 1.43)
- Atwater, Edward S. — Resignation from Board of Trustees, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 1.44)
- Backus, Truman S. (Professor of English 1867-83) — Letter to J.H. Raymond, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 1.45)
- Barnard, Henry — Letter to H. P. Jewett, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 1.46)
- Bawden, H. Heath — Papers relating to discharge from University of Cincinnati, resignation from Vassar, 1907-1911 (Box 1, Folder 1.47)
- Bequests to Vassar College, 1879-1954; [SEE ALSO: Lyon, Joseph B.] (Box 1, Folder 1.48)
- Bible Department, 1899-1900, 1901-1913 (Box 1, Folder 1.49)
- Biology Department — before 1889, SEE: Natural History Department
- Biology Department — Reports, 1889-1894 (Box 1, Folder 1.50)
- Biology Department — Reports, 1894-1902 (Box 1, Folder 1.51)
- Biology Department — Reports, 1902-1911 (Box 1, Folder 1.52)
- Biology Department — Reports and Correspondence, 1911-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1.53)
- Bishop, Nathan (Trustee 1861-1880) — Letters to J.H. Raymond, 1872-1875 (Box 1, Folder 1.54)
- Borden Fund — Correspondence, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 1.55)
- Buckland, Rev. R.J.W. — Letter to J. H. Raymond, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 1.56)
- Butler, William Allen (Trustee 1875-85) — Letter to President Caldwell, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 1.57)
- Caldwell, Samuel L. (President 1875-85) — Newspaper clippings and correspondence from Elizabeth Hamlin VC 1874 and others regarding President Caldwell, 1879-1885 (Box 1, Folder 1.58)
- Caldwell, Samuel L. — Letter, 1884 Apr 23 (Box 1, Folder 1.59)
- Caldwell, Samuel L. — Correspondence with Katharine P. Loring (Harvard University, Examinations for women), 1881; [3 letters] (Box 15, Folder 9.2)
- Cecil Pictures — Correspondence relating to Maure paintings and Sarah Cecil, VC 1884, 1896-1899 (Box 1, Folder 1.60)
- Chambers, Frank (trustee) — Resignation letter to Henry V. Pelton, 1920 May 27 (Box 15, Folder 9.3)
- Chapel — Attendance. Correspondence and statistics, 1916-1921 (Box 1, Folder 1.61)
- Chapel — Attendance: Faculty. Correspondence, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 1.62)
- Chapel — Hymnal. Correspondence and example, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 1.63)
- Chapel — Building specifications and laying of corner-stone, circa 1902-1904 (Box 1, Folder 1.64)
- Charter - SEE: Trustees. Charter
- Chemistry Department — "Mr. Vassar's artesian well - analysis by the chemistry class of 1877,", 1877 May 14 (Box 15, Folder 9.38)
- Chemistry Department — Reports, 1894-1897 (Box 1, Folder 2.1)
- Chemistry Department — Reports, 1897-1904 (Box 1, Folder 2.2)
- Chemistry Department — Reports, 1904-1911 (Box 1, Folder 2.3)
- Chemistry Department — Reports, 1911-1914, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 2.4)
- Choir — Petition for gowns, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2.5)
- Christian Association — Reports, 1910-1913 (Box 1, Folder 2.6)
- Church, Emma — Correspondence, 1863-1865 (Box 1, Folder 2.7)
- Circulars [Prospectus], 1864-1889 (Box 2, Folder 2.8)
- Class Day — Reports, 1893, 1896-1898 (Box 2, Folder 2.9)
- Class Day — Reports, 1900-1901, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 2.10)
- Class Day — Reports, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 2.11)
- Class Day — Reports, 1905-1908 (Box 2, Folder 2.12)
- Class Day — Reports, 1909-1911 (Box 2, Folder 2.13)
- College Avenue — Extension of College Avenue, 1868 Jul 25 (Box 2, Folder 2.14)
- Comptroller, 1941 Dec 15, undated (Box 2, Folder 2.15)
- Comptroller, 1942 Jan 12 - 1969 Jun 22 (Box 2, Folder 2.16)
- "Conscience Money": for stolen spoon - Letter, 1891 Dec 5 (Box 2, Folder 2.17)
- Corridor Teachers — Duties, letters to Miss Lyman, circa 1869 (Box 2, Folder 2.18)
- Corridor Teachers — Log Books, 1869-1875 (Box 2, Folder 2.19)
- Curriculum, resolutions, recommendations, reports, circa 1886-1910, undated (Box 2, Folder 2.20)
- Denominations of students, faculty, and teachers, 1865-1926 (Box 2, Folder 2.21)
- Dean, Willard L. — Letter from nephew and Bond Agreement with Vassar College for the position of Treasurer, 1893, 1896 (Box 15, Folder 9.4)
- Deane, John H. (VC Trustee) - Report on the estate of John H. Deane (printed), 1885 (Box 15, Folder 9.5)
- Denominational Statistics of VC [with 1872 letter from Nathan Bishop], 1865-1872 (Box 2, Folder 2.22)
- Directory — petition to publish directory, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 2.23)
- Drawing and Painting Department — SEE ALSO: Art Department
- Drawing and Painting Department — Applications for Professor of Drawing and Painting, 1861-1865 (Box 2, Folder 2.24)
- Drawing and Painting Department — Reports, 1865-1870 (Box 2, Folder 2.25)
- Drawing and Painting Department, 1870-1874 (Box 2, Folder 2.26)
- Drawing and Painting Department, 1874-1878 (Box 2, Folder 2.27)
- Drawing and Painting Department, 1878-1885 (Box 2, Folder 2.28)
- Economics and Sociology Department — Reports, 1893-1900 (Box 2, Folder 2.29)
- Economics and Sociology Department — Reports, 1900-1907 (Box 2, Folder 2.30)
- Economics and Sociology Department — Reports, 1907-1914 (Box 2, Folder 2.31)
- Economics and Sociology Department — Economics Department Survey Social Work of Former Students, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 2.32)
- Egyptian Collection, 1903-1904 (Box 2, Folder 2.33)
- Endowment, circa 1869 (Box 2, Folder 2.34)
- Endowment — Class Gifts, circa 1906-1910 (Box 2, Folder 2.35)
- Endowment — Plans for First Endowment $100,000, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 2.36)
- English Department — English [including Spoken English, Rhetoric and Belles Lettres] Applications B-D, circa 1861-1865 (Box 2, Folder 2.37)
- English Department — English [including Spoken English, Rhetoric and Belles Lettres] Applications E-W, circa 1861-1865 (Box 2, Folder 2.38)
- English Department — Course Material, undated (Box 2, Folder 2.39)
- English Department — Reports, circa 1860s (Box 2, Folder 2.40)
- English Department — Reports, 1865-1871 (Box 2, Folder 2.41)
- English Department — Reports, 1871-1878 (Box 2, Folder 2.42)
- English Department — Reports, 1878-1889 (Box 2, Folder 2.43)
- English Department — Reports, 1889-1892 (Box 2, Folder 2.44)
- English Department — Reports, 1892-1896 (Box 2, Folder 2.45)
- English Department — Reports, 1896-1899 (Box 2, Folder 2.46)
- English Department — Reports, 1899-1900 (Box 2, Folder 2.47)
- English Department — Reports, 1900-1902 (Box 2, Folder 2.48)
- English Department — Reports, 1902-1904 (Box 2, Folder 2.49)
- English Department — Reports, 1904-1905 (Box 2, Folder 2.50)
- English Department — Reports, 1905-1906 (Box 2, Folder 2.51)
- English Department — Reports, 1906-1907 (Box 2, Folder 2.52)
- English Department — Reports, 1907-1908 (Box 2, Folder 2.53)
- English Department — Reports, 1908-1910 (Box 2, Folder 2.54)
- English Department — Reports, 1910-1911 (Box 2, Folder 2.55)
- English Department — Reports, 1911-1914 (Box 2, Folder 2.56)
- Event Attendance Register, [circa 1887-1893] (Box 14)
- Examinations, Entrance Examinations and Certificates, Plans of Examinations, 1870-1883 (Box 2, Folder 2.57)
- Expense Accounts and Estimates, 1863-1869 (Box 2, Folder 2.58)
- Expense Accounts and Estimates, 1870-1879 (Box 2, Folder 2.59)
- Expense Accounts and Estimates, 1884-1902; [Notebook] (Box 2, Folder 2.59a)
- Expense Accounts and Estimates, undated (Box 2, Folder 2.60)
- Faculty — Applications - Teaching Miscellaneous, 1864-1865 (Box 3, Folder 3.1)
- Faculty — Appointments, circa 1865-1919 (Box 3, Folder 3.2)
- Faculty — Basis of Appointment and Promotion, 1911-1912 (Box 3, Folder 3.3)
- Faculty — Committees, 1867-1918 (Box 3, Folder 3.4)
- Faculty — Committee on Advanced Degrees, 1891-1906 (Box 3, Folder 3.5)
- Faculty — Certificate Committee, 1887-1895 (Box 3, Folder 3.6)
- Faculty — Certificate Committee, 1896-1905 (Box 3, Folder 3.7)
- Faculty — Committee on Commencement, 1895-1905 (Box 3, Folder 3.8)
- Faculty — Committee (Misc.) [Arranged Alphabetically], 1868-1902 (Box 3, Folder 3.9)
- Faculty — Curriculum Committee, 1888-1892 (Box 3, Folder 3.10)
- Faculty — Curriculum Committee, 1893-1895 (Box 3, Folder 3.11)
- Faculty — Curriculum Committee, 1896-1899 (Box 3, Folder 3.12)
- Faculty — Curriculum Committee, 1900-1902 (Box 3, Folder 3.13)
- Faculty — Curriculum Committee, 1903-1905 (Box 3, Folder 3.14)
- Faculty — Curriculum Committee, 1906-1908 (Box 3, Folder 3.15)
- Faculty — Curriculum Committee, undated (Box 3, Folder 3.16)
- Faculty — Committee on Degrees, 1887-1904 (Box 3, Folder 3.17)
- Faculty — Committee on General Catalogue, 1882-1883 (Box 3, Folder 3.18)
- Faculty — Committee on Excuses and Absences, 1891, 1904-1905, undated (Box 3, Folder 3.19)
- Faculty — Report of Special Committee on Evening Classes, 1914 Feb 23 (Box 3, Folder 3.20)
- Faculty — Committee Report, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 3.21)
- Faculty — Committee on Schedules, 1896-1897 (Box 3, Folder 3.22)
- Faculty — Committee Reports, 1915-1916, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 3.23)
- Faculty — Leaves of Absence, 1916-1919, undated (Box 3, Folder 3.24)
- Faculty — Petition Regarding Academic Costume, undated (Box 3, Folder 3.25)
- Faculty — Resolutions Upon the Deaths of Faculty Members, 1889-1898 (Box 3, Folder 3.26)
- Faculty — Salaries Report, 1899 (Box 3, Folder 3.27)
- Fire — SEE ALSO: Henry Noble MacCracken Papers
- Fire — Several Reports on Fire, 1918 Feb (Box 3, Folder 3.28)
- Fire — Reconstruction Work and Statement of Losses, 1918 Feb 12 (Box 3, Folder 3.29)
- Fire — Alarm Notice, undated (Box 3, Folder 3.30)
- Founder's Day, 1866-1892 (Box 3, Folder 3.31)
- Founder's Day, 1895-1892 (Box 3, Folder 3.32)
- Founder's Day, undated (Box 3, Folder 3.33)
- Fox, Alanson J. — Memorial statement draft from VC Board of Trustees, undated (Box 15, Folder 9.6)
- French Department — SEE ALSO: Ancient and Modern Languages
- French Department — Reports, 1869-1870, 1872-1882 (Box 3, Folder 3.34)
- French Department — Reports, 1882-1886, 1887-1890 (Box 3, Folder 3.35)
- French Department — Reports, 1890-1895 (Box 3, Folder 3.36)
- French Department — Reports, 1895-1896, 1902-1903 (Box 3, Folder 3.37)
- French Department — Sée, Rosalie - Correspondence with R. Wright and employment contract, 1879-1883 (Box 15, Folder 9.7)
- Gas Supply and Works — Gas Supply, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 3.38)
- Gas Supply and Works — Gas Works and Boiler House Construction, 1863-1869 (Box 3, Folder 3.39)
- Gate Lodge — Construction, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 3.40)
- General Education Board — Letter to Henry V. Pelton, 1916 Feb 24 (Box 15, Folder 9.8)
- General Superintendent, 1867-1912 (Box 3, Folder 3.41)
- Geology and Mineralogy Department — before 1879, SEE: Natural History Department
- Geology and Mineralogy Department — Reports, 1879-1892 (Box 3, Folder 3.42)
- Geology and Mineralogy Department — Reports, 1892-1897 (Box 3, Folder 3.43)
- Geology and Mineralogy Department — Reports, 1897-1901 (Box 3, Folder 3.44)
- Geology and Mineralogy Department — Reports, 1901-1914 (Box 3, Folder 3.45)
- German Department — Reports, 1873-1885 (Box 3, Folder 3.46)
- German Department — Reports, 1885-1894 (Box 3, Folder 3.47)
- German Department — Reports, 1894-1898 (Box 3, Folder 3.48)
- German Department — Reports, 1898-1903 (Box 3, Folder 3.49)
- German Department — Reports, 1903-1910 (Box 4, Folder 3.50)
- German Department — Reports, 1910-1914 (Box 4, Folder 3.51)
- Gifts, 1887-1934 (Box 4, Folder 3.52)
- Greek Department — SEE ALSO: Ancient and Modern Language Department
- Greek Department — Reports, 1889-1898 (Box 4, Folder 3.53)
- Greek Department — Reports, 1898-1903 (Box 4, Folder 3.54)
- Greek Department — Reports, 1903-1914 (Box 4, Folder 3.55)
- Grounds — Plan for Improving the Grounds, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 3.56)
- Grounds — Application for Groundskeeper, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 3.57)
- Hague, William H. — Correspondence and memorial statement on Hague from VC Board of Trustees, 1871, undated (Box 15, Folder 9.9)
- Higher Degrees, 1885-1907 (Box 4, Folder 3.58)
- History Department — including History and Economics
- History Department — Applications, 1856-1864 (Box 4, Folder 3.59)
- History Department — Reports, 1865-1866, 1887-1889 (Box 4, Folder 3.60)
- History Department — Reports, 1889-1892 (Box 4, Folder 3.61)
- History Department — Reports, 1892-1894 (Box 4, Folder 3.62)
- History Department — Reports, 1894-1897 (Box 4, Folder 3.63)
- History Department — Reports, 1897-1901 (Box 4, Folder 3.64)
- History Department — Reports, 1901-1908 (Box 4, Folder 3.65)
- History Department — Reports, 1908-1914 (Box 4, Folder 3.66)
- History Department — Reports, 1914-1918; [photocopies] (Box 4, Folder 3.67)
- Housekeeping Order Book, 1880-1882 (Box 15, Folder 9.39)
- Housing — [Faculty and Students], 1874-1923 (Box 4, Folder 3.68)
- Infirmary letter, Elizabeth B. Thelberg - James M. Taylor, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 3.69)
- Innis, George — Letter from [?] Winslow, memorial statement draft from VC Trustees, 1873, undated (Box 15, Folder 9.10)
- Insurance, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 3.70)
- Janitor's Office, undated (Box 4, Folder 3.71)
- Janitor's Office — Application for Position of Janitor, 1863-1865 (Box 4, Folder 3.72)
- Jewett, Milo P. — Letters to Sarah J. Hale, 1864; [2 letters with transcripts] (Box 15, Folder 9.11)
- Jewett House, 1906-1908 (Box 4, Folder 3.73)
- Kapp, Caecilia (Prof. of German) — Letter from J. H. Raymond, 1877 Jul 25 (Box 15, Folder 9.12)
- Laboratories, undated (Box 4, Folder 3.74)
- Laboratories — Vassar Brothers Laboratory, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 3.75)
- Lady Principal — [Applications], 1861-1864 (Box 4, Folder 3.76)
- Lady Principal — Correspondence, 1871 (Box 4, Folder 3.77)
- Lady Principal — Correspondence [Circular letters to parents], 1867-1872 (Box 4, Folder 3.78)
- Lady Principal — Guidelines (Box 4, Folder 3.79)
- Lady Principal — Report, 1865-1869 (Box 4, Folder 3.80)
- Lady Principal — Report, 1869-1871, 1872-1875 (Box 4, Folder 3.81)
- Lady Principal — Report, 1875-1880 (Box 4, Folder 3.82)
- Lady Principal — Report, 1880-1885 (Box 4, Folder 3.83)
- Lady Principal — Report, 1885-1891 (Box 4, Folder 3.84)
- Lady Principal — Report, 1891-1896 (Box 4, Folder 3.85)
- Lady Principal — Report, 1896-1900, 1901-1902 (Box 4, Folder 3.86)
- Lady Principal — Report, 1902-1903, 1906-1914 (Box 4, Folder 3.87)
- Latin Department — SEE ALSO: Ancient and Modern Language and Literature; Greek and Latin Language and Literature; Ancient Language
- Latin Department — Reports, 1889-1896 (Box 4, Folder 3.88)
- Latin Department — Reports, 1896-1901 (Box 4, Folder 3.89)
- Latin Department — Reports, 1901-1907 (Box 4, Folder 3.90)
- Latin Department — Reports, 1907-1914 (Box 4, Folder 3.91)
- Laundry — Specifications for Building, 1872 (Box 4, Folder 3.92)
- Leases — Davies Property, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 3.93)
- Leases — Windsor Hotel Lease, 1895 Aug 1 (Box 4, Folder 3.94)
- Lectures, 1879-1887 (Box 4, Folder 3.95)
- Legal Actions, 1881-1909 (Box 4, Folder 4.1)
- Legal Actions — Fayerweather Will Case, 1893-1896 (Box 4, Folder 4.2)
- Legal Actions — Gill - Hiestand Case, 1875-1882 (Box 4, Folder 4.3)
- Legal Actions — Mary Monroe Will, 1895-1897 (Box 4, Folder 4.4)
- Library — Librarian Rank (Box 4, Folder 4.5)
- Library — Selection of Librarian, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 4.6)
- Library — Librarian's Annual Reports, 1867-1883 (Box 4, Folder 4.7)
- Library — Librarian's Annual Reports, 1883-1891 (Box 4, Folder 4.8)
- Library — Librarian's Annual Reports, 1891-1897 (Box 4, Folder 4.9)
- Library — Librarian's Annual Reports, 1897-1903 (Box 4, Folder 4.10)
- Library — Librarian's Annual Reports, 1903-1911 (Box 4, Folder 4.11)
- Library — Librarian's Annual Reports, 1911-1913 (Box 4, Folder 4.12)
- Library — Librarian's Annual Reports, 1913-1914 (Box 5, Folder 4.13)
- Library — Librarian's Annual Reports, 1914-1918, 1923-1924 (Box 5, Folder 4.14)
- Library — Librarian's Annual Reports, 1924-1927 (Box 5, Folder 4.15)